thank you and uh good evening everyone
and thank you for joining the uh
earnings conference call of ics lombard
for q1 fi 2021
uh i would like to give you a brief
overview of the recent developments in
the industry
and uh and our responses to them post
which our cfo mr gopal balachandran will
share the financial performance of the
company
now as you you know we know this and you
know as we speak today we are seeing
rising cases of covet 19 in the country
when that's happening and there is a
level of uncertainty surrounding the
pandemic
you know that remains various major
measures taken by policymakers to
restart commerce and trade are showing
results
as such we believe that the complete
halt of activities that we witness in
april may be behind us
and the new normal may well be about
learning to live with the virus
following safety protocols but ensuring
a gradual return to normalcy
at icc lombard we believe that it is
important to take extra measures to
support our customers in these
challenging times
forcing the forcing the difficulties
arising due to the pandemic we decided
to provide some relevant covers to our
customers
accordingly we have launched a number of
covet 19 specific health insurance
products
we have also revamped our existing
health insurance products by adding
customer centric features
for new customers purchasing a health
insurance policy we reduce the waiting
period to launch a kobe 19 related claim
from 30 days to 15 days this is a
initial wait period that we have
considering the economic uncertainty
financial security has gained utmost
significance for our customers so we
decided to retain the cumulative bonus
accumulated by customers over time
even if they launched a covert 19
related hospitalization claim
in the normal circumstances this would
not be so
most importantly we added home health
care benefit
for our customers preferring to avail
treatment in the safety and comfort of
their homes
rather than getting hospitalized to
highlight these upgraded
health insurance solutions we have
launched a new health insurance focused
campaign
restart right i hope all of you seen the
during our earnings call for fy 2020 we
had shared with you a host of digital
initiatives that we took to service our
customers
and enable our channel partners to
conduct business we continue to give
thrust to adoption of these digital
platforms in the quarter under review
review our new mobile you know service
app i'll take care that was extended to
the retail customer segment
crossed one lakh thirty thousand
downloads enabling more and more
customers to avail its insurance and
wellness solutions at their fingertips
the teleconsult feature available
through this app enable customers to
seek medical advice
from the safe environment of their home
in case of property segments
we harness virtual platforms and
technology platforms including drones
for conducting claim service remotely
for small value marine claims we
introduced a do-it-yourself
mode empowering our customers to conduct
self-assessment of the damage
and receive real-time claim approval
from our customer service team
for the diverse set of stakeholders
including customers investors etc i
would like to appraise
you that we have begun integrating ehc
principles across our businesses
towards this we have implemented
policies and initiatives aimed at
scaling up our efforts towards
sustainable value creation
let me now talk about the industry
trends in the last few weeks we have
been witnessing signs of
green shoots across sectors as more and
more industries adapt
to digitization and restart operations
business activity should continue to
grow
the non-life insurance industry which
witnessed a blip
in the in the first quarter q1 of 2021
should register a growth in the coming
quarters we believe
for the recently concluded quarter the
general insurance industry registered at
the growth of 4.2 percent
uh you know in q1 of 2021 over q1 2020
uh with the industry gdp moving down to
uh rupees 393.29 billion rupees
in q1 2021 from 410.72 billion rupees in
q1
of fi 2020. this is as per gi council
report
excluding the prop segment the jack the
generations industry
grew at 3.2 percent to rupees 378.54
billion rupees
in q1 2021 as compared to 391.08 billion
rupees in q1
of fi 2020. now within this the segments
such as motor insurance has been
severely impacted during the lockdown
and but they're now gaining uh some
the month of june uh for the segment has
witnessed signs of recovery
though we are still far from the long
term average
on the other hand health insurance
has benefited from the heightened
concern around the health hazard
and measures taken by the government as
new health insurance policies
registered in upsurge we believe that
the pandemic may well
be a trigger for the segment to witness
significant increase in penetration in
the near future
now as far as the commercial lines are
concerned the fire segment continued to
show robust growth
due to uh the rate hike with effect from
january 1 2020
we've talked about this in the past
marine and engineering lines
witnessed the growth due to the slowdown
in economic activity
however as the economy is steadily
improving and given the digital adoption
by the segment we expect
to see a rebound since our fi 2020
results call we've
witnessed new regulatory announcements
that are focused on policyholder
benefits
these include uh first the launch of
standardized health insurance policy
called rfg sanjeevani with effect from
april 1 2020
wherein the authority has allowed
insurers to determine the price on
compliance with specific norms
initially under the policy the sum
insured allowed was between
rupees one lakh to five lakhs further
the authority by
ydh circular dated july 7th allowed the
insurers to issue policies with some
insured less than 1 lakh
and greater than 5 lakh which and this
has to be in multiples of
50 000 rupees the second has been the
withdrawal of
withdrawal of the option of long term
package effectively
august 1st 2020 this means that new
vehicle customers will not be able to
avail
own damage covers on long term basis
going forward
this is expected to have marginal impact
on business and profitability
uh allowing general and health insurance
to this is the third one allowing help
general and health insurance to offer
both indemnity and benefit-based
short-term health insurance policies for
covert 19.
it also prescribed a standard
benefit-based health policy and a retail
standard health policy under the
nomenclature's covet rupture policy for
benefit
and uh and corona court coverage policy
for indemnity respectively while the
corona coverage policy
was mandated to be offered on or before
july 10
2020 insurers were encouraged to offer
the corona raksha policy by july 10
2020. now as i conclude my address i
would like to summarize that we are well
positioned to navigate through this
dynamically changing risk environment
given the strength of our franchise
diversity diversified product and
distribution portfolio and most
importantly the trust of our customers
we we continue to remain focused on
creating long-term value for our
shareholders
uh through prudent risk selection and
sustainment sustained profitability
i'll now request gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently
concluded quarter thanks bhagav
and good evening everyone hope everyone
is staying safe and healthy
i will now give you a brief overview of
the financial performance of the company
for the quarter ended june 30 2020.
we have put up the results presentation
on our website you can access it as we
walk you through the performance numbers
the gross direct premium income of the
company stood at rs 33.02 billion in
quarter one
as compared to rupees 34.87 billion in
quarter one of the last year
a d growth of 5.3 percent excluding crop
segment our gdpr decreased to rupees
32.74 billion in this quarter
as compared to rupees 34.88 billion in
quarter one of last year
registering a deal growth of 6.2 percent
our gdpri growth was primarily driven by
our focus on preferred segments
consequent to the increase in minimum
prescribed rates for certain occupancies
under fire segments
this segment registered a robust gdpa
growth of 41.6
in quarterback 2021 thereby aiding the
gdp growth of our property and casualty
segment
as indicated in our results presentation
the overall property and casualty
segment grew by twenty point five
percent in quarter one twenty twenty one
over quarter one twenty twenty on the
retail side of the business
sme and agency channel and health
indemnity continue to grow faster
and remain our areas of focus to harness
the potential of these segments
we have been expanding our distribution
network so as to increase penetration in
tire 3 and tire 4 cities
our individual agents which include the
point-of-sale distribution
were 4982 as at june 30 2020
as against 47548 as on march 31 2020.
the long-term motor penetration for
private cars stood at
19.8 percent for quarter one 2021
from 17 in quarter one of 2020
and for two wheelers it stood at 11.3
percent for quarter 1 2021
from 17.5 percent in quarter one twenty
twenty
the advanced premium was rupees 30.31
billion
as at june 30 2020 from rupees 30.25
billion as at mass 31 2020.
combined ratio stood at 99.7 percent
in this quarter as compared to 100.4
percent in quarter one of last year
combined ratio was 98.4 in this quarter
excluding the impact of cyclone amphen
and nisarga
which had an impact of 0.31 billion
rupees as compared to
99.7 percent in quarter one of last year
excluding the impact of cyclone fanny
which had an impact of 0.16 billion
rupees
our investment assets rose to rupees
281.18 billion as june 30 2020
as compared to rupees 263.27 billion at
mass 31 2020.
our investment leveraged net of
borrowings was 4.23 times
at june 30 2020 as compared to 4.21
times
at mass 31 2020. investment income
decreased to rupees 4.99 billion in
quarter 1 this year
compared to rupees 5.27 billion in
quarter one of last year
mainly on account of lower capital gains
our low our capital gains was lower by
56.1 percent
at rs 0.60 billion in quarter one this
year
compared to rupees one point three eight
billion in quarter one of last year
our profit before tax grew by eleven
point seven percent to photo
is five point three three one billion in
this quarter compared to rupees four
point seven five billion in quarter one
of last year
on account of lower capital gains
consequently
profit after tax grew by twenty eight
point five percent to rupees three point
nine
eight billion in quarter one this year
as against rupees
three point ten billion in quarter one
of last year primarily due to the lower
effective tax rate of
25 return on average equity was 25.1
percent for this quarter
as compared to 23 for quarter one of
last year
solvency ratio was 2.5 times at june 30
as against 2.17 times at mass 31 2020
continued to be higher than the minimum
regulatory requirement of 1.5
as i conclude my address i would like to
reiterate
that we ended quarter 1 2021 with a
diversified product portfolio and
healthy financials
we continue to focus on prudent
underwriting technological prowess
and introducing relevant and timely risk
management solution for our customers
we will stay focused on driving
long-term growth in a sustainable
balance
i would like to thank you all for
attending this earnings concerts call
and we will be happy to take any
specific questions that you may have
thank you
thank you very much we will now begin
the question and answer session
anyone who wishes to ask questions may
press star and one on the touchstone
telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue i press star and two
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking questions
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question q assembles
to ask questions please press star in
one
the first question is from the line of
shreesh ganpati from macquarie
please go ahead yeah hi uh
good evening everyone um bdj i'm seeing
after a long time
that you have had an underwriting profit
now if i
were to look uh i have a closer look
there has been a good claims as well as
expense management
i mean uh how long do you think i mean
how much of this is sustainable
has it got to do with the fact that the
lockdowns have been there and therefore
the things have been lower
or work from home has resulted in lower
expenses just something
more qualitative that you can share on
the uh
overall claims as well as expense
management the second question
is the retail indemnity of course has
done very well again any anecdotal
evidence or qualitative
feedback from corporates are they really
going for more of these group policies
that people are taking more
retail internally based products that's
something which we would like to know
and finally uh the motor od and third
party losses have actually gone down
quite substantially
the loss ratios whereas fire marine
engineering has picked up is it just a
seasonal thing or
maybe something uh something got to do
with some even which is occurred this
particular quarter
so let me uh address the third one first
it's you know
short response so let me get it done
with uh you know
this quarter we had the cyclone uh
you know losses that gopal talked about
uh and one or two
uh marine losses uh non-cyclone related
that's why
and as you know these businesses are
episodic uh it could be that in a
certain quarter you'll have a loss so it
will go up but on an average
for the year is what we look at these
numbers so as i said the quarterly
volatility
doesn't really you know uh really
concern us in that sense we would look
at what is the picture over there
over the whole year and cyclone hampfun
particularly had
some impact in terms of the
underwriting number and the
sustainability thereof
look there has been obviously some
benefit on the claim side uh this
quarter in terms of frequencies uh
coming down
uh and if you look at different segments
this is in line with what we talked
about in may when we were doing the
last quarters earnings for last year's
earnings call
we had said that we would expect and we
were seeing some reduction in frequency
in the motor side
we had also talked about the frequency
reduction and the health side when it
came to
the planned surgery cases
now as you understand you know at this
point in time unless you really need to
go to the hospital no one is going would
want to go to a hospital
so these are benefits that has come
through uh and we all
also said that we will see some of these
going up uh
you know in as things stabilize and it's
and it normalizes
uh the way we have looked at this is
these are
not something that so for example uh
health uh
in health uh we while there
has been a benefit in the quarter uh our
approach to reserving and
and actual practice is a bit
conservative uh we
do uh you know worry about uh covet
claims going up eight is going up
as we speak so we wouldn't want to take
the full benefit of the
reduced frequency in the first quarter
and then end up having to have a very
high
frequency in the last quarter so we
would want to watch this for a whole
year period
and then take a call on on what is the
appropriate loss
for the year so there is uh you know so
there is some benefit but it's not
entirely kind of factored in the first
quarter numbers
in terms of in terms of cost look
obviously like every company
we are looking at all uh you know in
essence unnecessary cost
that we can cut down upon these are
some obvious areas which everyone will
be doing
but certain areas where we believe it
makes sense to invest
we are actually investing so one uh
you know as a company we've actually
given increment to our people uh
we had given performance bonus in the
first quarter uh you know today in the
board meeting you've
i decided on the increments or for for
people
and we are we are seeing opportunity in
this
at this point in time for the long term
because we believe we
can see this as an opportunity to invest
in the future so there would be
possibilities that we may even increase
our head count
going ahead so it's not the savings on
the fixed cost is not on the employees
side and employees cost is our biggest
cost element
so savings will be in terms of other uh
you know areas of cost that we can uh
contain
and do remember that for us the sourcing
cost is a you know large part of the
cost
so if we have lower retail numbers in a
period
the sourcing cost is also low uh you
know for that quarter
and lastly on technology we are actually
you know we've decided to increase our
technology budget
and uh you know invest more and we see
in the long term
the experience that we've had in this
period in the long term we believe
we will take some positives out of this
in terms of the way we work
the way we operate how much we work from
home how much
of flexibility we provide how much of
further investment in digitization we
are at a certain level related to the
market but still
uh we believe this time to keep
investing and stay ahead of the curve
and that's an area where we are further
uh seeing how we can
invest lastly your second question in
terms of
indemnity yes you're right i mean there
is as i said you know
in the covering uh you know opening
remarks also i made the point that there
is
a higher demand for indemnity both from
the corporate
and even more from the retail side one
thing you'll remember
is that our retail health book and you
know if you see our overall health book
there is a corporate segment there is a
b2b2c segment
which is business that we source through
our bank assurance partners
it is fundamentally detailed but it gets
classified under group because it's
b2b2c
and third is a pure b2c which is retail
indemnity that we sell largely through
agents etc
the retail indemnity business has done
really well
but the b2b2c obviously because banks
are not dispersing as much as they were
in the past that has been grown
so on balance we are uh we are quite
happy with the
health opportunity and the growth that
we are seeing at this point in time and
we believe it is uh it is potentially a
step change in terms of demand for
health insurance in the long term and
you know one of the things that we are
seeing is not just new customers we are
also seeing
existing customers ask for uh someone
should increase
thanks thanks uh and that's a good
demand for the standardized health
products right
we think it will have a decent demand in
certain markets
certain segments of the market i think
it's a good product that
the regulator has launched it will
probably uh increase penetration in
segments which otherwise you are not
buying health insurance
thank you
thank you the next question is from the
line of shreya shivani from clsa
please go ahead yeah
thank you for the opportunity so uh i
was going through the slide which talks
about the
impact of catastrophic events and uh
uh we know that in uh for general
insurers
there is a catastrophic uh trigger that
after level
uh you will actually have their
catastrophic bonds which will get
triggered so can you throw some light on
since we had certain cyclones and floods
this quarter and also with kovac 19
going on
uh if you can really talk about uh how
are we
managing the uh losses in the
catastrophes that are going around and
how close or far
are we from that trigger which uh you
know which will trigger the bonds the
catastrophic bonds
thank you so sure we are not
catastrophic bonds these are
uh you know cat reinsurance that we buy
every company buys and it
it triggers not in a sense that you have
to accumulate losses for the year and
then
it triggers uh it is an even best
trigger so
when a cyclone happens if the aggregate
losses cross
that threshold that we uh you know we
buy the cover from
then the reinsurers pay and we have to
you know then we have to spend a little
bit of money which is pre-agreed
you know to reinstate that cover so
basically what it does is
very high uh very large cat losses
our balance sheet is protected and we
pay a fee to buy that production it's
almost like you're buying motor
insurance for your motor car
uh you know it's like our book that we
are protecting throughout the insurance
cover it's not a cat bond
and in terms of specifics of what has
happened so even this year
uh when the arm fun happens aggregate
claims may be x
in fact that's slightly gone above our
uh you know triggered threshold so it
will trigger and we will get some
uh return from the uh ranger but you
know
our balance sheet is and all of that is
actually factored into the quarterly
numbers that you've seen
gopal you want to add anything yeah i
think the only thing that i will just
add is i think in line with
what we have communicated uh i think the
trigger point for
a catastrophic uh loss in terms of
what's the hit that we take on the p
l that number is about 25 crores and uh
of course uh so that's the that's the
maximum heat that we take in the event
of any catastrophic uh
event that arises and over and above
that as bargain explained i think
obviously
depending on the extent of recovery that
we make on the reinsurance program
we will obviously have to pay the
extraval cost
so so far as the current couple of
catastrophic events are concerned
in so far as cyclone amphen is concerned
i think the extent of losses that came
and hit on the net
is in excess of the 25 crores threshold
so
that's so to that extent our clearance
is impacted by 25 crores
and the excess will be paid by the
reinsurers and in so far as cyclone
nissarg is concerned i think that has
not had a large impact in so far as our
claim numbers are concerned
in the aggregate as we mentioned as a
part of the opening remarks
both of these events put together on the
claims we have had an impact of about 31
crores
okay thank you sir understood
thank you the next question is from the
line of
age oxford frederick from bnk securities
please go ahead
uh thanks for checking my question sir
sir my
question is regarding health and what
strategies are we adopting to utilize
this big opportunity that's out there
that's one and two is uh
the competitive slowdown is because of
banks slowing down and
what portion of our business is coming
through banks particularly the
independent
and individual so that's uh on health
sir
yeah so again and i'll ask sanjeev to
expand on this
uh the answer to the second part is yes
as i said uh
you know because we have a larger uh
part of our
health distribution and these are not
necessarily indemnity this includes
retail benefit products and since we
traditionally have a larger
footprint from the bankishan's
partnership side on the retail health
the impact on health for us has been uh
you know
pretty severe on that end uh just to
give you a sense
last year we had roughly about 68 of our
uh
retail business and this retail includes
pure retail as also the b2b2c that i
talked about
68 of the business was uh you know
business that
we got from the uh these kind of
partnerships
and 32 was uh you know pure direct one
two and one on sales
uh that number from the industry will be
very different it will be probably very
high for one-on-one sales and very low
for practitioners so
that definitely has had some impact for
us this quarter
but within that the agency piece which
is
uh you know individual sales that's done
really well
uh for us and while it's not cover up
the uh you know
uh gap on the vanquishon site but it's
uh
it's uh relatively uh you know
outperformed is our view
of what's happened on the market in
terms of the strategy um
look uh you know there are multiple
levers of strategy
one of course is the whole focus on
product and distribution
and you've seen a whole host of you know
products that we've launched
recently one of the things that we've
been doing for the last two years is
significant and significantly expanding
on our agency distribution
as i said bankruptcies are already
already strong
and there's been some regulatory changes
in the about three four years back
which has also triggered this initiative
from our side
there are certain constraints that have
gone away uh for us
and and that's something that we are
driving the other thing that we are also
doing is uh
the entire approach that we are taking
to health is
to say that we are not just focusing on
pure sickness insurance where you go to
a hospital and we
pay the reimburse the claim we are
thinking through
with a very customer-centric uh you know
point of view
in terms of what all do you really worry
about as an individual and can we find
solutions to each one of them
uh so one of them being why this
hospitalization why can't we cover
you know outpatient care uh you know
care and
for group customers and b2b2c customers
we've launched
uh opd covers uh last year uh that's uh
that was doing quite well i mean you
know the bankruption speed has
gone a bit slow this quarter but so
that's one for example and there we've
worked
with network of partners digital health
players
telecalling you know telehealth
companies
uh you know wellness service you know
companies and all of this is
being provided on a digital platform
it's an app
which we call i'll take care i talked
about that in my opening remarks
uh and in this period one of the things
that we did want to drive was this you
know in the long term also we've been
wanting to drive this digital health
and but in this period that was
obviously something that we kind of
scaled up included home health care
because you know for small
you know issues at this point in time no
one wants to go to a
hospital but it that doesn't mean our
customers should suffer so we've
actually
tied up service with service providers
to provide home
uh you know care for you for our
customers uh for covered or non-covered
cases both so these are you know very
very uh you know
uh first to the market kind of
initiatives that we've already
uh launched and uh we believe the long
term that we have you know we have to
come
look at the complete healthcare service
for a customer rather than just
ipd which as of now mostly most of the
market just focuses on
sanji we want to add anything i think
pretty much well covered and one of the
key things that
we have also seen is the customers on
the retail side in particular on the
internet
part have started looking as having a
health policy more from an investment
standpoint rather than an expense
mentality so
one of the few things which is changing
and helping us on ground also
to drive on indemnity fund benefits i
think as bargain also mentioned
will build up uh as and when
disbursements come in because benefit
traditionally is more of an asset
protection
based cover which will happen as we see
our banking partners and our mbs
you know progressively start dispersing
each one of them is
i i think till at least last one getting
their you know credit strategy in place
and we would probably see a relatively
better quarter two than what's happened
in quarter one on that
uh yes perfect sir and just a point on
the lost phases of health
uh so compared to q4 we saw it slightly
deteriorating
so uh like 70 to 75 percent
so how should i read that one you want
to explain that
so ajax what happens is i think loss
ratio is purely a function of
uh what mix of business that you write
uh
and as we had kind of explained
in terms of corporate generally tends to
have a relatively
higher loss ratios as compared to let's
say the extent of loss issues that you
will get to see
on the retail indemnity portion so
that's one
the second element is with respect to
when you look at health health also
includes
the retail benefit component and in this
quarter
as you would have seen the extent of
loss ratios that you would have
the benefit portfolio contribution is
relatively far lower
and generally benefit is a profitable
book
on the aggregate when you look at the
overall loss ratios
for health quarter four was roughly
about eighty four point eight i mean
quarter one of this year is at eighty
five point seven
so in that sense it's not a material
movement in terms of the overall numbers
it's purely a function of what mix of
business that you write quarter one
generally tends to be far more
heavy in terms of corporate because bulk
of the corporates tend to renew their
policies
and q4 generally tends to be more
relatively skewed in terms of retail
where the general loss experience of the
retail indemnity book
is lower so it's clearly a function of
the mix of those
and just to add one more point while you
shouldn't look at just the loss ratio
because the expenses are different
across these two
two categories the b2b the
corporate business pure corporate
business employer for you know where we
cover employees the
distribution cost is relatively less uh
pure retail uh the distribution cost is
higher so when we look at the business
we look at
uh in aggregate the combination
got it sir sir and uh this new products
like karaoke fantasy and all these
corvette related products uh so what is
your sense uh like going forward
okay let's forget forward but this
arrogance and jimmy
uh do you think uh uh like
that portion will grow uh substantially
and
do you think that that makes more money
for you or your
your play products are making more money
structurally speaking
going forward what we've done is we've
kind of segmented the market
we believe that there is a segment of
market which
today was not buying the traditional
covers or
typical medi-claim policies uh you know
that we sell through our
you know retail agency force because of
expense maybe it was expensive
maybe you know each one of us have our
own terms and conditions so maybe it was
getting too complex for the retail
customer uh
so this the whole thought process behind
this from the regulator was to have a
very standardized product so there is no
dissonance or gradually at least the
hope is that there won't be any
dissonance in terms of
understanding of what you bought so if
what you if you bought a standard
arguments engineering product from
insurer a versus interior b
there is no difference so it will and i
we strongly support this thought process
because we believe that in the long term
in a very underpinning market like india
it is important to
build credibility on the product and in
a product like insurance if you have too
much variation
while it is fine for maybe slightly more
sophisticated customers for
you know new to the category customers
it's good to have a
basic product that they understand
easily so it will we believe open up a
market for
uh that segment of customers also
geographically
and you know in terms of income profile
there could be
because these are slightly restricted
covers uh
uh it's not as full blown as some of the
other covers that we have
so it's slightly cheaper so we uh
expect a certain segment of customers uh
you know wanting to buy this
now profitability will depend on whether
we've done the segmentation
right and whether we are actually
bringing new customers to
the book rather than cannibalizing our
existing customers that's something that
we have to watch very very closely
uh but we believe in the long term this
is a very positive development
it will depend on the execution in terms
of whether we actually get it get the
benefit
thank you before we take the next
question we'd like to inform
participants that in order that the
management is able to address
questions from all participants in the
conference please limit your questions
to two per participant
should you have a follow-up question we
request you to rejoin the queue
you take the next question from the line
of anshudayani from edelweiss
please go ahead
anshu deyani from edelweiss you may go
in with a question
there seems to be no response from the
line of uh ancient
we move to the next question the next
question is from the lion of madhukar
ladda from hdfc securities please go
ahead
uh hi everyone uh thanks for taking my
question
uh so can you give us some color on how
renewals in a motor have behaved
during the lockdown are we seeing
similar levels
in tp and in od separately
and are we seeing you know lapses happen
uh some some thought process some colors
over there will be helpful
yeah i think we talked about the fact
that in april the renewals were
slightly down uh you know given the
leeway that was given
uh to you know by the regulator to renew
if customers wanted with the lag
that was not surprising and also given
what was happening on the ground
what we had anticipated was that people
will come back and renew a bit later so
the renewal rates for uh t plus one as
in you know what
you know when i said t what people who
renew within the same month
versus people who renew the next month
or renew in the next one
month after that those percentages have
gone up uh so in a sense we've kind of
been recovering the reduction in renewal
rates that we saw in the april
and this is increasing every month sanji
we want to give any more color to that
no absolutely right so reserve is what
happened in april
uh where they were the gap for delta was
almost
12 to 15 percent uh if we talk about
june exit
it's pretty much close to what we had
pre-covered level in terms of anyone
still marginalness
but nothing much to worry about and we
do believe that
we will have a decent renewal because a
lot more mobility has also started
across the country and
uh consequent to that people who
actually disordered in the month of
april and they should come back and seek
renewal so we are pretty much sorted on
that and there was a dispensation
from the regulator till the may 15th and
zero volts and after that
uh these customers also renewing it so
we don't see
for any challenge on private car and tp
any which way
for the new stock that was sold last
year has a long-term duration so
any which way the customer has been
having a long-term policy on that
got it that's it from my side all the
best
thanks thank you the next question is
from the lineup
from nippon india mutual fund please go
ahead
yeah hi sir uh you you have written a
crop this year
uh i mean it's very small i understand
one percent but maybe does the thought
process are you seeing that the markets
that the rates have
i mean hardened and that is why you know
it's just an old policy because the data
comes in with a lag
from the government at times so it's an
old
policy we've not written anything new
okay answer secondly on health insurance
uh you talked about you know that uh
covert could be an inflection point for
uh selling of uh hell products but if i
look at the mix the mixed system
it's q towards b two b rather than b two
b slash b to b to c
so uh uh maybe some thought process as
to why is that so that in quarter one
because i would have assumed quarter one
the fear would have been the highest
and hence the pole demand should have
been the highest but
a big surprise when i saw that the
individual numbers are flat on a y of y
basis when it comes to the mix
uh sanjeev i i'll say that so with
respect to quarter one being highest uh
i think
sequentially the demand is picking up uh
when the lockdown came in which was at a
very sharp level at that point of time i
think
even the consumers were kind of you know
discovering themselves so from that
perspective now the demand is picking up
even if you look at it internationally
china the most of the growth in
indemnity health based products have
happened post the kuwait
crisis getting over so we do believe
that we are also having a similar
uh pattern when it comes to demand for
this product coming up
in fact you know just to add to what
sanji was saying uh april was slow
because
as he explained everyone was probably
thinking of other issues
june retail uh health numbers have been
very very robust for us
and we believe for the industry as well
so the exit would have been higher than
what it would be for the quarter average
right is that a fair understanding
yes absolutely and on the just to give a
small indication even the
quarter four which typically has the
highest level of agency partners being
active
we have seen uh what's happened in the
month of june in particular we have seen
numbers higher than
uh march month or you know gender march
month agency activation numbers also so
we're seeing a very very robust uh
growth and we see all measures in
bhargava explain in terms of what we
have done
has also helped in market
probably approaching ics lombard
products just to add on to that product
i think if you look at
the june exit while you would have seen
the quarter one new
indemnity growth rate at 26 percent if
you look at the exit for the month of
june the new indemnity growth has
actually been about 77 percent
wow wow okay and so lastly just within
this employer employee uh
is it i mean because there was one
regulation in between wherein you know
every company had to take this policy or
had to cover its uh employees for the
forward
related uh disease so is it because of
that you're seeing a spike and within
this what's the mix between large
corporate mid and small
middle smes if you can get that that
would be really interesting so that was
mha but that has not been uh it's not
getting followed through
so you don't think that it may have had
some initial spike but now that's not
the
uh factor in terms of mix gopal you want
to
answer so i think largely i think pratik
what we have always said is uh
we have tried to keep the grand
portfolio as granular as what we can
our approach pretty much remains the
same uh on the b2b part of the business
uh we have uh so in that sense uh in
terms of the overall mix
the portfolio of large corporates will
tend to be much lower than
the sme portfolio that we have that we
write so for example if you have seen
the sme segment continues to kind of
grow robust
on an aggregate basis not specific to
health if you have looked at that has
grown at about 30 percent but the
portfolio mix is more skewed towards
relatively small and
mid-corporate accounts as compared to
large uh corporate uh
accounts that we would have written
great thank you so much and all that
thanks thank you the next question is
from the line of sun kate goda from
spark capital
please go ahead yeah
thanks for the opportunity so just again
hopping on
the health point so if i look at
absolute numbers retail indemnity
or individual healthcare business
classified in your presentation
that has seen a decline but but we say
that the
new indian meeting has grown by 26
percent so this wanted to understand
how do i uh add up the numbers because
the group others
where i believe b2b2c fits that
contribution has also come up
so so so really um trying to tie the
number
why the retail health
so that is first question and the second
question is
is largely with respect to the motiv
loss ratio which is which is at around
70 percentage right now
um do you think this loss ratio is
sustainable
uh uh because because 70 looks to be too
good and
and despite despite our to doing the
contribution
coming off a bit in in in first quarter
uh compared to what it was uh for the
full year of last year and the most
controversial
so so even if the mix is moving in favor
of
other products so maybe severity or
intensity
are higher uh the long faces and motor
tp has improved so this just wanted to
understand the point so i'll ask gopal
to answer the second the first question
on the health on
the on the moto uh tp side uh
you know as we've discussed many times
what we should look at
is the number for the whole year rather
than
just a quarter number we may have had
some benefits in terms of for a quarter
uh you know either some releases here or
the fact that frequency was lower in
this quarter so you should watch the
number for the whole year
having said that overall the trend in
the tp side is pretty positive we are
seeing frequency drops sustaining
um in terms of mix that you said the mix
is not deteriorated similarly
in fact our cv book is makes us come to
about
14 15 2 wheeler is about 27 still
actually private car has increased in
the mix
but we do as we've said uh since last
quarter we are actually
gradually increasing our cv exposure a
bit
again cautiously because we are seeing
some opportunities
uh given underlying changes in in
behaviors
so on tp we are we are feeling
reasonably comfortable there may be some
volatility in in loss ratios
in a particular quarter with another
quarter but on balance i think we are
reasonably uh happy with the tp book
that we write
uh the industry situation we can't
commit
on the health uh gopal you want to
explain the now in numbers
the issue is the same that i said you
know right you know b2b2c which is
through the bank assurance has come down
uh which has not been we've not been
able to compensate that
with the retail indemnity growth that we
sell through agents in spite of the
numbers that gopal talked about
but gopal you want to give more color to
uh yeah sure
sure so sanket if you look at the total
retail
book in terms of health uh for quarter
one last year that number was roughly
about
3.4 billion this includes both benefit
as well as
indemnity put together this quarter that
number is down to about 2.2 billion
now obviously a large part of this
decline it is contributed by
the number that parker spoke about in
terms of the benefit portfolio not
clearly having a significant decline on
so far as the individual segment is
concerned within retail
that number is actually increased from
1.5 billion
1.47 billion to 1.82 billion so that's
actually an increase of
23 this is the aggregate retail
health indemnity within that is what we
mentioned about the new retail in
liberty growth was 25
for quarter one and for the exit month
of june
new retail health indemnity was seventy
seven percent
okay about the group just to clarify
when i do the numbers when you have
given in the presentation
19.5 percentage as individual and 2.1 as
uh
in the current year uh the number comes
to the
individual health after 1.7 and 1.6
uh for for last year and currently
respectively so i see a decline around
of nine percentage so still still i
am not able to figure this out that 1.5
billion and
1.8 billion what you are trying to say
uh yeah
that doesn't get thrown uh get
which you have disclosed in the
presentation so when you look at the
presentation
what happens is obviously there is some
element of indemnity that goes and sits
as a part of
detail which is the number that you
would look at absolutely and equally
there
will be some element of indemnity
business that will sit as a part of
group others
so when you look at which is where i
kind of gave the breakup for you
in terms of aggregate indemnity book
that number has increased from as i said
1.5 billion
to about 1.82 billion
thank you before we take the next
question a reminder to participants to
please limit your questions to two per
participant
the next question is from the line of
nishan chandra from temersec
please go ahead uh
thanks for taking my question i had uh
two points one is
uh with respect to the playing speed
uh especially on motor what have seen
our
release policies from prior period uh
especially on cp between march 31 and
june 30. has there been a
revision in terms of assessment of uh
actuarial base that we have there the
second one is on
the shared value account piece uh if i
remember correctly for the quarter
ending march i think we have taken some
sort of an environment with respect to
the book uh what has been the stance
given recovery in market
in quarter ending june i think it
reversed or because i couldn't see that
clearly from the financials i could see
a change in high value
account but i couldn't see whether it
was uh done to a reversal of employment
or it was just through the
fair value so uh
this reversal of impairment no we've not
done any
yes we have done our impairment because
of the sharp correction in the month of
march
things have recovered but we've not done
a reversal of impairment we normally
don't do that i mean
we believe that's slightly aggressive in
approach so
we don't do that if whenever we sell the
particular stock
we will uh while we could i mean
theoretically yes we could but we
generally don't do that number one and
in the in terms of the provisioning
sorry the reserving policy there's no
change in the policy nation it's the
same thing which
basically every quarter in fact you know
as i've been you know sharing every
month they are actually underwriting
finance sales all of us sit together and
look at
the book you know which are the books
which which we believe
makes sense to focus on etc but on the
reserving side they actually looks at
numbers on a quarterly basis and bases
his assessment
if he believes that there is some
somewhere we need to send them something
somewhere
the data is competing that we have to
release we do the release
so it could be that in a certain quarter
it's not as if everything happened at
the end of the year
it could be that in certain certain
lines you could take because
now because if there has been a release
in motor tp uh given that it is a
quarterly
number that we are seeing now and it
could potentially be spread over the
full year
the 70 is not really a extendable thing
so the steady state is somewhere
far higher of 70 but there has been a
release which is pulling that down to 70
percent that's how i interpreted it
so as i explained earlier uh you know
the releases
you know need not be spread over the
whole year
equally in terms of the frequency drops
that we've seen
we've also not been over aggressive in
booking all of those
for the reason that i articulate because
we want to watch the claims pattern over
the year
and then take a call for the year and
and just looking at the
uh presentation it seems like
the releases have come from uh periods
prior to fi twenty years
can you just repeat that again no so if
i look at the table
at the end of the appendix of the
presentation my understanding is that
the releases
all pertain to f519 and before and not
for f520 so
i just wanted to understand if my
understanding is correct so what happens
nishant in so far as loss experiences
are concerned
i think it's purely a function of the
loss development that we get to see
across portfolios
as we have explained earlier in respect
of short tail lines
the releases tend to be much faster and
in respect of some of the long tail
lines obviously we wait for certain
periods of development before which we
can take a call on the reserving numbers
so what you get to see is purely a
function of most of the short tail lines
that we would have written
and then of course if basis development
even in the long tail lines if we get to
see
a need for reserving to be relatively
lower then to that extent one would
calibrate the reserves uh
accordingly but fy20 is too near for
that to happen
thank you the next question is from
rishi jinjunwala from iifl
please go ahead yeah thanks for the
opportunity
um so just uh following up on the
previous question and maybe
specifically on motor od right um
you know because of the country was
being locked down for almost
you know two months and partial
lockdowns for the rest of uh
the june as well just wanted to
understand i mean clearly
the number of claims that would have
come on local ruby would be
substantially lower
but what we see in terms of claim ratios
uh the improvement
is not that stark um so are we
like uh provisioning for claims not
reported or any of that
in terms of smoothing of how the plane
ratios play out for the rest of the year
because i'm assuming it's a you know
unlike pp uh
it's a 12-month thing and and if if
claims haven't come in three months um
then at least for that quarter the
number should have been much better
rishi it's the same philosophy as i said
uh
in one of the you know questions one
could
take the full benefit in a quarter but
we don't believe that student because
we also talked about it in may in may
and i just repeat the point that we
believe that people will
use vehicles a bit more when they have
to
you know rather than using public
transport so you don't want to have a
situation
where you take the full benefit in a
quarter and then uh to the latter half
of the year your frequency goes up
sharply and your you see a huge swing so
we would i think it's appropriate to
watch the number for the year rather
than take full benefit in a quarter
so you're provided for more in this
quarter that's what's right
so we we do a actual estimate
and uh you know which is a ulr estimate
and that ulr extreme is using data over
a long period of time
you know one blip may not immediately
impact the ulr numbers
of course the fact that frequency has
come down in the near term
will have some impact but we would want
to watch the data over a period
and as i said you know for short till
business let's say like od we will want
to
do it in a year uh for long tail it will
be even longer
and secondly on on help can you just
you know get some numbers of data points
in terms of
where we are or on on kovic related
claims
um versus where the industry is if it
all you have these numbers and
and how do you expect it to rise and
where it could potentially be as a
proportion of
your normal claims that you typically
have just trying to understand basically
you know incrementally how much of uh
you know the health claims could be
uh coming from the courthouse right
you have the numbers in the covet and i
can talk about the expectations for the
future after that
um so uh if you look at
rishi i think uh the number of uh kovit
claims largely i think as what we
explained
uh with respect to this particular
quarter i think we have seen more of
uh more of
claims coming in respect of kovit
treatment for the quarter
obviously that number is roughly in
excess of a thousand claims
so as to speak it's closer to maybe
about uh 1200
300 claims is what we would have seen on
the overall uh
covet policies and the amount involved
is
roughly about 20 crores or so so that's
the impact for us
with respect to kovit cases yeah and for
the future
rishi is you know we are staying
cautious we are
uh i you know i don't think anyone
would have predicted a one million
number by this time
uh while right from beginning we have
been saying if you remember that you
know
uh the the the risk is high in this if
things don't uh
kind of taper out sooner so even in the
in in the may call we talked about the
fact that the frequency for non-covet
claims have come down
but we would have to watch the covet
claim so uh
you know again it's very difficult to
predict this uh and say that this will
go up to a certain level
the numbers are increasing uh it's not
something that is
causing any uh you know very large
concern at this point in time or panic
at this point in time
but it's something that we are watching
with with a lot of
caution but on balance we
given the benefits on the other side the
non-covet claims have come
we are hopeful that aggregate for the
year
would not be out of line in terms of the
loss ratio
but it we could be wrong and covet could
go out of control that's the
that's the caveat that i will give in
terms of predicting anything on the loss
ratio on the health side
thank you the next question is from the
line of ninten from investing asset
management
please go ahead uh thanks for the
opportunity sir
uh so can you comment on the frequency
on the motor od and motor tpa
in the month of june and house is
compared from pre-covet level
and are we seeing the frequency
reference frequency similar to those or
lower than that yeah so april the
frequency was very very low
uh for obvious reasons and every month
we've seen significant increase in the
frequencies
june month ah you know at this point in
time would still be maybe 15-20 percent
frequency lower than
pre-covert on the motorod side but uh
you know it's a very rapid increase from
what we saw in in
in april which is also kind of in line
with expectation because
uh for the reason that i talked about uh
you know earlier and even now i think
some of the bigger cities
the vehicle usage is still muted so we
are uh you know kind of in line with our
anticipation and expectation we believe
the frequency will go back to normal
uh uh you know in in due course
which is the reason why we are saying
this should be looked at with the annual
length rather than a quarterly length
sure secondly what is the reason for the
business promotion expense
remaining flat because i believe this
year the state this quarter the
sale from the motor side has been quite
muted in the decline so what is the
reason for business promotion expense
being similar on a quarter on quarter
basis gopher you have the answer
so that's primarily because i think it's
purely a function of what kind of
uh opportunities do we see in terms of
growth
and as we are kind of explained i think
in this quarter relatively the kind of
volumes of
opportunities that one would have seen
has been far lower than
what we would have seen in the past and
as we look forward and
obviously the growth momentum looks
positive
and to that extent one would calibrate
the extent of sales promotion expenses
that
one would incur in the current quarter
purely driven by the extent of
opportunities that we see on the
revenues and to that extent is why
why you get to see the sales and
promotion expenses pretty much
remaining constant
is it a variable line item or it's a
fixed line item so
going forward
so as i said i think it will be purely a
function of the opportunity that one
one sees in case if you believe that
there are opportunities to kind of
ride incremental growth then obviously
we will calibrate and see what is the
extent of sales and promotion expenses
that one will have to incur
so it will not necessarily be a cost of
a fixed structure
unlike what you see in terms of employee
cost or let us say infrastructure
expenses
those all are expenses which will be in
that sense completely fixed
but so far as advertisement sales
promotion marketing
those are expenses that we calibrate
this is the opportunity that one sees
so for example you would have also seen
in the month of july we kind of launched
a campaign
in order to kind of restart the health
opportunity that one sees
so those are uh avenues through which we
look at
uh playing this through and to answer
your point
it will not necessarily be a cost um
thank you the next question is from the
lion of udit karivala from ambit capital
please go ahead hello am i audible sir
yeah yeah so my question was
that in terms of the cat reinsurance
which you explained
and the cap of around 25 crores is that
for
catastrophic events or let's take if you
have two events in a year
uh it will be 25 plus 25. so can you
give some
sense around that yeah the answer is yes
and you know basically it's a
it's a treaty that you signed at the
beginning of year which
says and there is a certain clause which
basically says that
loss within the seven days uh is what is
covered as one cat event uh but let's
say three months but
as gopal explained we pre agree
uh cost to reinstate the cover and the
finite number of read statements that
are also agreed
so you reinstate the cover um and the
reinstatement cost depends on
how big was the claim so if the uh
if the reinsurance paid 10 crores i mean
you took 25 crores reinsurance to 10
crores not available
and again it crosses 25 crores again
we'll take a state of 25 crores
and again the reinsurance will pay the
balance but
so in case of kovat how high kobit
is not calculated you know covert is
different cover it is a pandemic
so on that is why you said that it could
go out of control because that would not
be
yeah covet is not covered by you know
pandemics globally are not covered
because it
is not coverable by insurance without
support
you you would have an unlimited loss
kind of uh
yes if it you know really goes out of
control and uh
you know as a country we are not able to
uh kind of bring it under
control yes that is a risk we are hoping
and at least our models are not showing
something like this at this point in
time which is why we are saying
we are watching it with caution it is
not something that we are kind of
over worrying it about because on the
non-covet side there are
equally some savings but on balance
that's a risk that we carry at this
point
and one last thing which is related is
that if you said around 1200 to 1300
claims in first
quarter and the payout was around 20
crores so which roughly means that the
uh each claim on an average was upwards
of 1.6 lakhs
um if i go back to the calculation which
was shared earlier
like in 4q was that you know 50 60 000
kind of is what the management was
estimating given the treatment cost may
not be high which is not
standing out right so can you give some
sense around that because
yeah you know if you've seen the press
and the uh the overall narrative on what
is happening on
the cost of covert treatment and the
reaction of even the policy makers on
what's happening
it's obvious that the treatment costs
have been surprisingly high compared to
what
probably everyone felt is reasonable
and i think this is one issue that is uh
becoming quite an issue with between the
pair and the provided industry
uh because uh you know we are finding
some very
you know in essence outlier claims which
we believe is unreasonable
and what it does is uh you know even if
let's say we end up
paying for the customer it really
affects them
it's not that the customer is not
affected we may be paying the claim but
what happens is if you have a five like
some insured
and a claim that logically could have
cost one lakh and it becomes a three
lakh
you have left with now two lakh cover
for the rest of the year because you've
consumed three lakh of your sum insured
uh so this is an issue that is becoming
quite uh not only with the policy makers
and you've seen
you know actions by state supreme court
etc but equally between
the insurance industry and the hospital
industry there's a lot of negotiation on
debate going on on what is reasonable
and fair
as we see there's been a lot of debate
and negotiation and arguments that are
going on right now
i think the costs are completely out of
uh control in certain places
and there needs to be some
reasonableness to the cost
thank you we'll be able to take one last
question
we take the last question from the line
of nation chavati from kotak
please go ahead
hi am i honorable now yes you are nice
okay just uh one or two things uh what
has really happened on the solvency side
i think the solvency ratio has increased
this quarter
okay so nation um i think uh what we
kind of also explained
last quarter is i think when you look at
the solvency uh
in so far as uh two three uh aspects
one is with respect to the fair value
change account movement that you had
seen
in so far as solvency regulations are
concerned on the equity side
the regulation disregards any gains if
at all
is there on the mark to market position
on the reporting date
however if there is a loss that has to
be considered for the purposes of
solvency
and if you would have seen on 31st of
march we had a mark to market loss of
roughly about 430 crores
that was considered as a part of the
solvency uh computation on 31st march
as at 30th june if you would have seen
our mark to market
on the equity portfolio as as compared
to 430 crores of loss
is has ended the portfolio with a 38
crores of loss
so that clearly is a function of uh the
movement that one sees in so far as
improvement in solvency is concerned the
second is also purely a function of what
you get to see
in terms of incremental revenue growth
in this quarter i think pretty much
similar to what the industry is
experiencing
uh one has seen a relatively lower top
line growth
uh already growth to the extent of let's
say four five percent or so
and that by itself also kind of
contributes to the uh
uh improvement in solvency and the third
factor
is let's say the performance in terms of
our operating
outcomes on the profits that we make is
also a contributor to the
overall solvency numbers so a factor of
all the three is what has
led to the increase in solvency moving
up from 2.17 to 2.5
so and uh did you share the number for
advanced premium for the quarter
i think last whatever last year was
30.25 at 31st march that number at 30th
june is 30.31
it's almost kind of flatterish and just
one last question was on the outlook for
uh you know for of competition in motor
roading segments
i think we are you know this time around
we have seen uh some improvement in the
loss ratios out there so
should we say that the worst of the
competitive phase on the motorola
side is behind us is difficult to say
yes
um and as i've been saying
maybe for the last two calls i think
last maybe about 18
months to 24 months the industry has
been hurt a lot with
on the other side because of aggressive
competition
and our take was that whether people can
sustain that
um but you know right now because of
everything that we are saying the
frequency is dropped
so one can't rule out continued
aggression on od site uh having said
that as i said you know as
freedom frequencies come back uh the the
short benefit of maybe one or two months
may not sustain
in which case it will be very difficult
for people to be further aggressive on
the other side
od loss issues are probably
unsustainable for
most companies at this point just one
last one
uh you know on the covet side i think
what you uh what you highlighted was
that you
that your four policy claim is around
two lakh rupees
so i think you you yeah you pointed to a
number like close to that
so i was wondering about a number which
is a lower number than that but anyway
tell me yeah
so uh what do you uh i mean where do you
think this number really settles down i
guess with the negotiations etc that
happens with the hospitals
look uh you know again as we speak there
is a lot of
uh you know discussion and negotiation
going on uh
i won't want to hazard a guess on this
call and give you a
guidance that i could be wrong with uh
obviously we are trying to attempt to
bring it under control
um our sense is that it's at this point
in time it's not reasonable cost
uh but it depends on many factors right
location
the severity the comorbidity which which
links it to the length of stay for the
patient
uh whether the case is mild severe
critical
so there are many factors and the mix is
what determines finally the cost because
you know hospitals also have to get a
fair cost if it's a critical case in icu
ventilator etc versus someone in the
mild just being
kind of under observation so it depends
on all of the mix
but
okay thank you very much all the best
thanks question thank you very much
we'll take that as the last question
i would now like to have the conference
back to mr bharara gabriela for closing
comments
now thank you everyone thanks for
joining us uh at this time
and uh you know and again uh wish all of
you
uh good health and take care of yourself
thank you